<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>尘灰先生</title>
  
  <subtitle>Life is Now</subtitle>
  <link href="http://example.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://example.com/"/>
  <updated>2023-08-01T13:08:02.190Z</updated>
  <id>http://example.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>尘灰先生</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>保单整理——附表格</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/p/140ab620.html"/>
    <id>http://example.com/p/140ab620.html</id>
    <published>2023-08-01T11:28:47.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-08-01T13:08:02.190Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p> <strong>整理是清醒的内心反映在外部世界的表现。—-王阳明</strong></p></blockquote><p>据说，90%的人买了保险，</p><p>2个月后，会忘记保障内容；</p><p>6个月后，会忘记保险种类；</p><p>10个月后，会忘记保司名称；18个月后，只记得买过保险。</p><h2 id="保单自查"><a href="#保单自查" class="headerlink" title="保单自查"></a>保单自查</h2><p>如何判断我是否需要保单整理？<br>很简单，保险总是需要解决问题的——我们从问题出发：试着回答下面几个问题</p><ol><li>您每张保单的缴费时间、缴费账户都清楚吗？</li><li>您知道您的保单什么时候领钱，可以领多少吗？</li><li>您所购的保险，你知道什么才可以获得理赔，该怎样理赔，赔多少？</li><li>作为保单非常关键的要素——受益人，您的每张保单是否指定了呢？他们分别是哪些人？<br>你是否都能清晰回答？</li></ol><p>如果你有不清楚的，那么本文会产生价值，请继续阅读。</p><h2 id="保单整理？"><a href="#保单整理？" class="headerlink" title="保单整理？"></a>保单整理？</h2><p>想象一下，你的保单就像是一本珍贵的宝藏藏在家中的混乱储藏室里。</p><p>当你最需要时，却找不到它，遗忘了它。</p><p>假设发生了一场突发意外，你急需向保险公司提出索赔申请。但是，由于过去几年里你购买了多份保险，这些保单被散落在不同的抽屉、文件夹和信封里。你不记得确切的保险产品名称和相关信息，更不用说索赔时需要提供的文件了。</p><p>在这种情况下，没有进行保单整理就像是找针在大海里找针一样困难。</p><p>而且因为对保险不熟悉，导致很多本可避免的麻烦发生。</p><p>比如，</p><ul><li>保险索赔的时限是有要求的，通常是2年的有效期。</li><li>超过保险的缴费宽限期它就会失效的，通常是60天的宽限期。</li><li>没有明确的受益人会在领取带来很多不必要的麻烦。</li><li>等等。。。。</li></ul><p>而如果你进行了保单整理，所有的保单将被有序地整理、分类和电子存档。</p><p>当突发事件发生时，</p><p>你只需要打开一个电子档一份打印好的文件。</p><p>立即找到需要的保单，轻松提出索赔申请，确保你的权益得到及时保障。</p><p>它可以帮助你节省时间、降低压力，确保你在需要时能够迅速找到关键的保单文件，保障你和家人的财务安全。</p><p>此时，保单整理，会让我们对保单心中有数，时刻有效。02</p><h2 id="谁需要"><a href="#谁需要" class="headerlink" title="谁需要"></a>谁需要</h2><p>广义上，大家都应该定期检视自己的保单；狭义上，也可以透过以下几个问题来判断：</p><ol><li>我的保单至少两年以上没有看过了。</li><li>我不能准确的回答我住院了保险公司最多能给我报销多少？</li><li>我不能准确的回答我买了哪些险种（或是我的保障范围有哪些）？</li><li>近期有一些转变，例如刚参加工作、刚换工作、刚结婚、刚生子、刚贷款买车买房等等。</li><li>我的保单是我爸妈买的。</li><li>我的年缴保费超过我的年收入两个月以上。</li><li>我的保单是人情单（碍于情面不得不跟亲戚或朋友投保）。</li><li>我的业务员不见了，我是孤儿保单。</li></ol><p>若以上你有一项以上是有的，或许你就应该重新整理自己的保单了。</p><h2 id="整理三步"><a href="#整理三步" class="headerlink" title="整理三步"></a>整理三步</h2><p>保单整理、保单检视、保单跟进</p><p>彻底弄清“交钱”！“领钱”！“赔钱”!“留钱”！<br><a href="https://imgse.com/i/pPCwOVU"><img src="https://s1.ax1x.com/2023/08/01/pPCwOVU.md.png" alt="pPCwOVU.md.png"></a></p><p><strong>第一步——保单整理：查询、备份、记录。</strong></p><p><strong>第二步——保单检视：范围、保额、配置。</strong></p><p><strong>第三步——保单跟进：调整、告知、预约。</strong></p><p>最后得到——直观的数据汇总+详细的保单情况。</p><p><a href="https://imgse.com/i/pPCwXaF"><img src="https://s1.ax1x.com/2023/08/01/pPCwXaF.md.png" alt="pPCwXaF.md.png"></a></p><p><a href="https://imgse.com/i/pPCwj54"><img src="https://s1.ax1x.com/2023/08/01/pPCwj54.md.png" alt="pPCwj54.md.png"></a></p><p><strong>尘灰先生希望每一份家庭保单都能通过保单整理，避免发生下面这几点，</strong></p><ul><li>保障遗忘（忘记已生效的保障，忘记理赔）</li><li>保障幻觉（合同约定与期望不符，影响理赔）</li><li>保障浪费（多余的保障，比如重复报销型医疗险）</li><li>保障不足（责任增加保额没增加）</li></ul><p>我们通过定期整理检视家庭的保单，目的是为了方便日后查阅、管理和处理保单相关事务，保持保单文件的安全性和可用性。</p><p>无论是个人还是企业，保单整理都是一个重要的管理工作，可以帮助您更好地掌握保险信息，避免不必要的麻烦，并在需要时及时找到相关的保单内容。</p><h2 id="服务"><a href="#服务" class="headerlink" title="服务"></a>服务</h2><p><strong>保单整理，找尘灰先生！</strong></p><p>如果你刚好需要保单整理服务，想更好的优化自己的保单配置，请联系你身边的专业顾问。</p><p>也可直接关注尘灰先生后在后台联系咨询，获得完整保单整理服务。</p><p>————–<strong>限时免费</strong>————–</p><p>如果你想要领取表格，也请关注尘灰先生后台私信，打赏任意金额，小偿领取。</p><p>————–<strong>远离白嫖</strong>—————</p><hr><p><strong>END</strong></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">整理是清醒的内心反映在外部世界的表现。-- 王阳明</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="保险" scheme="http://example.com/categories/%E4%BF%9D%E9%99%A9/"/>
    
    <category term="工具" scheme="http://example.com/categories/%E4%BF%9D%E9%99%A9/%E5%B7%A5%E5%85%B7/"/>
    
    
    <category term="保单整理" scheme="http://example.com/tags/%E4%BF%9D%E5%8D%95%E6%95%B4%E7%90%86/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Who Are You</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/p/768f730c.html"/>
    <id>http://example.com/p/768f730c.html</id>
    <published>2023-07-30T08:55:08.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-08-01T12:07:23.087Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p> ** Identify Yourself As A Winner **<br>我由我自己定义。</p><blockquote><p>本文价值：Who Are You ！</p></blockquote><span id="more"></span><audio id="audio" controls="" preload="none"><source id="mp3" src="https://aod.cos.tx.xmcdn.com/storages/8a9a-audiofreehighqps/FA/90/CKwRIRwEHlEyADGs4QCQsdjf.m4a"></audio><p>If you want to change your life, I mean radically improve your life, you must first change your perception of yourself. It comes down to beliefs, because at the end of the day, no matter how hard you work, no matter how many hours you put in, if you don’t believe you can do it, you won’t do it. You won’t do it, because when you get to that impossible moment, you’ll quit. You’ll procrastinate. You’ll come up with all sorts of excuses because you don’t believe you can do it.</p><p>如果你想改变你的人生，我的意思是，彻底地改变你的人生，你必须首先改变你对自己的看法。这一切都与信念有关，因为不管怎么样，无论你工作得多卖命，无论你付出了多少时间，如果你不相信自己可以改变人生，那你就做不到。你做不到，是因为当你遇到困难的时候，你会放弃。你会耽误时间。你会编造出各种各样的借口，因为你不相信自己真的可以改变人生。</p><p>But if you identify yourself as someone who does achieve that particular thing, when you get to those impossible moments, you will rise to the occasion! You will rise! You will rise because you will believe you can do it. Even if there’s only 1% of people in the world capable of achieving it, you’ll believe you are in that one percent. Because you identify yourself as a winner, you identify yourself as someone who will do whatever it takes, someone who is willing to go through the pain to get to the other side. You identify yourself as someone who will win, in the end, no matter what.</p><p>但是，如果你认为自己是一个真的能够有所成就的人，当你遇到困难时，你就会迎难而上！你会走上坡路！你会往高处走，因为你相信你能做到。就算世界上只有百分之一的人有能力做到，在那时你也会相信自己就是那百分之一。因为你将自己视为胜者，将自己视为一个愿意为此付出所有努力的人，一个勇于接受历练煎熬去越过高峰的人。无论如何，你会将自己看作终将胜利的人。</p><p>Think about habits and addictions you want to change. If you’re a smoker for example, no matter what processes you go through to change your habit of smoking, you’ll never change it long term if you still identify yourself as a smoker, if you see the process as hard, or see it like it is taking something away from you. It’s taking away your stress release, or whatever story you tell yourself. You see, the people who quit smoking without cravings, they do so because their new identity has changed. They’re not smoking anymore. Smoking is equal to death. Smoking, the bad habit, is viewed as something that takes away from their life, not adds to it. It’s the same for any habit, any addiction, anything you want to change in your life.</p><p>想一想那些你想改变的习惯和嗜好。比如，如果你是个烟民，不论你戒烟要经历何种困难，只要你还认为自己是个烟民，只要你认为这个过程过于困难，或者认为这会让你失去一些东西，那么你就永远无法长期戒烟。你看，那些成功戒烟的人，他们能够做到这样，是因为他们在心中为自己树立了新的形象。他们再也不会吸烟了。吸烟等于死亡。他们认为，吸烟这个坏习惯百害而无一利。这和其他习惯、嗜好或者任何你想改变的东西，道理都是一样的。</p><p>Change your identity, and change the meaning you give to that thing and you’ll be able to remove it and replace it with something that takes you to a much better place, somewhere you actually want to be. You’ve got to take a moment, by yourself and ask some deep and honest questions. You might want to write these down. Ask them, write your answers, then after that, write down how you want to see yourself.</p><p>改变自己的身份，改变你赋予它的意义，你会将旧的意义抹去，用能让你变得更好的意义去替换它。你必须花点时间好好问自己一些深刻的、诚恳的问题。也许你会想把它们写下来。问自己这些问题，并写下你的答案，然后写下你希望如何看待自己。</p><p>So, what is your current identity? How do you view yourself? In regards to your health, how do you view yourself? Are you someone who is healthy? Are you someone who has discipline to eat foods that make you stronger every day? Are you someone who exercises every day? If no, why not? If yes, can you train better, harder, differently so you feel at your peak every day?</p><p>那么，你现在的身份是什么？你是如何看待自己的？健康方面，你如何评价自己？你是一个健康的人吗？你能自觉地吃那些让你的身体更强壮的食物吗？你每天都会运动吗？如果你的回答是不，为什么？如果你回答是，你是否能更有效、更努力、甚至换种方式去锻炼来让自己每天都处于最佳状态呢？</p><p>In regards to your achievements in life, can you do more? If yes, why haven’t you? What is holding you back? Do you enjoy what you do for a living? What can you change to enjoy it more? How would you describe yourself in 3 sentences? Write it down. If you were to explain your qualities and struggles in 3 or less short sentences, to a complete stranger, how would you describe yourself? Write down whatever comes to your mind. This is not about being perfect or looking good. This is private. This is honest and if you’re real and ready it will lead to change.</p><p>关于你现在的成就，你可以去争取更多吗？如果可以，为什么你还没做到？是什么拖了你的后腿？你享受你的工作吗？你能通过做出什么改变来使自己更享受这份工作？如果要用三个句子来描述自己，你会怎么说？写下来。如果让你用短短的三句话来向一位陌生人描述你的品质和遇到的困难，你会如何描述自己？想到什么就写什么。这不是说要让你显得很完美或很体面，这是私下的交流。这是真诚的描述。如果你足够诚恳、做足了准备，那么改变就会发生。</p><p>Now, write down how you want to see yourself. Picture one year from today. Imagine yourself one year from today after all the daily work you’ve put in to transform your life. Look at yourself from a birds-eye view. You’re looking with pride because you are the exact person you want to be. You created this. You built this character.</p><p>接下来，写下你想看到怎样的自己。构想一下一年后的今天。想象一下，一年后的今天，你在付出了这么长时间的、日积月累的改变人生的努力之后，你会是什么样的。从鸟瞰的角度看一下你自己。你内心感到自豪，因为你就是那个你想成为的人。你创造了这一切，你锻造了自己的角色。</p><p>Now write down what qualities this person has. Write down in 2-3 short sentences who this person is. Is it someone who is completely authentically themselves? Is it someone who you see smiling all the time, someone with great relationships, someone who lights up everyone they come into contact with? Is it someone who has a crazy amount of physical energy? Someone who has unbreakable discipline – but that discipline comes easy? Is it someone that makes life look easy and fun? Someone who has created the wealth and happiness exactly as they pictured? Is it someone who learns and applies that learning to achieve results? Is it someone who keeps going and going and going? Who is that person?</p><p>现在，写下这个人所拥有的品质。用两三个短句描述一下这是谁。他是一个真实的自己吗？他是一个经常将笑容挂在脸上的人的人吗？是一个拥有良好的社会关系的人吗？是一个能为他周围的人带来光亮的人吗？他是一个精力充沛的人吗？他是一个极其自律、且自律对于他而言轻而易举的人吗？他是一个让生活安适又有趣的人吗？他是一个能创造出自己所期许的财富和幸福的人吗？他是一个不断学习并用学到的东西获得成就的人吗？他是一个坚持不懈的人吗？他是谁？</p><p>Now, write one sentence. Who are you now? I am… I am someone who lives with passion. Someone who is disciplined with ease. I am someone who only consumes that which makes me stronger. Food. Learning. People. I am someone who lives every day to the fullest and pushes myself every today so I am stronger every tomorrow. I am someone who knows exactly where they are going so I only take actions that get me closer to that place in every area.</p><p>接下来，写一句话。现在，你是谁？我是……我是一个怀着热情去生活的人。我是一个能自如地做到自律的人。我是一个只做能让我更强大的事的人。吃有益的食物，终身学习，与优秀的人交往。我是一个将每一天都活出极致的人。我是一个不断鞭策今天的自己、去成就明天更优秀的自己的人。我是这样的一个人：我目标明确，无论是在什么方面，我都只做让我不断靠近我的目标的事情。</p><p>Who are you?</p><p>你是谁？</p><p>Who are you?</p><p>你是谁？</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt; ** Identify Yourself As A Winner **&lt;br&gt;我由我自己定义。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;本文价值：Who Are You ！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="阅读" scheme="http://example.com/categories/%E9%98%85%E8%AF%BB/"/>
    
    <category term="励志" scheme="http://example.com/categories/%E9%98%85%E8%AF%BB/%E5%8A%B1%E5%BF%97/"/>
    
    
    <category term="获得能量" scheme="http://example.com/tags/%E8%8E%B7%E5%BE%97%E8%83%BD%E9%87%8F/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hello World</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/p/undefined.html"/>
    <id>http://example.com/p/undefined.html</id>
    <published>2023-07-29T07:32:05.904Z</published>
    <updated>2023-07-29T07:32:05.904Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to <a href="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</a>! This is your very first post. Check <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/">documentation</a> for more info. If you get any problems when using Hexo, you can find the answer in <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/troubleshooting.html">troubleshooting</a> or you can ask me on <a href="https://github.com/hexojs/hexo/issues">GitHub</a>.</p><h2 id="Quick-Start"><a href="#Quick-Start" class="headerlink" title="Quick Start"></a>Quick Start</h2><h3 id="Create-a-new-post"><a href="#Create-a-new-post" class="headerlink" title="Create a new post"></a>Create a new post</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo new <span class="string">&quot;My New Post&quot;</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/writing.html">Writing</a></p><h3 id="Run-server"><a href="#Run-server" class="headerlink" title="Run server"></a>Run server</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo server</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/server.html">Server</a></p><h3 id="Generate-static-files"><a href="#Generate-static-files" class="headerlink" title="Generate static files"></a>Generate static files</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo generate</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/generating.html">Generating</a></p><h3 id="Deploy-to-remote-sites"><a href="#Deploy-to-remote-sites" class="headerlink" title="Deploy to remote sites"></a>Deploy to remote sites</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo deploy</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/one-command-deployment.html">Deployment</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to &lt;a href=&quot;https://hexo.io/&quot;&gt;Hexo&lt;/a&gt;! This is your very first post. Check &lt;a href=&quot;https://hexo.io/docs/&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; for</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
